Florin LIPAN

About

I'm a Ruby developer with a strong devops background and leadership experience. I've taken various lead roles in the past and like to engage with all sides of product development. I know my way around AWS, Ansible, Kubernetes, Docker and Debian-based systems. I have a personal interest in languages like Crystal and Rust. I've been a full stack developer before and know a thing or two about HTML, CSS and Javascript. I value clean, simple, boring code and try to be pragmatic while keeping my standards high. I can write concise, well structured documentation. I enjoy learning, teaching and being self-organized.

Da		001
PP	เรก	กลเ

Email <u>florinlipan@gmail.com</u>

GitHub / Projects https://github.com/lipanski

Website / Blog https://lipanski.com
Place of residence Berlin, Germany

Languages Solid English, German, Romanian. Some French.

Experience

May 2020 - Present Chatterbug / Senior Software Developer

Jul. 2018 - Apr. 2020 Blacklane / Head of Engineering (Platform)

A partially hands-on management role. I'm providing high-level technical guidance to the Blacklane Platform teams (Infrastructure, Geolocation, Payment, Back-office, Salesforce, Internal APIs), trying to empower developers whenever I can, but getting my hands dirty when I'm needed. I'm handling recruiting and interviews, providing feedback in 1:1 sessions and mentoring team members. I'm trying to keep engineering standards high, apps running smoothly and people engaged and happy.

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2018 Blacklane / Lead Backend Developer (Ruby)

A merry mix of backend development, devops, software architecture and management tasks. I helped tame the Rails monolith, designed and partially developed the new Booking API and developed various (micro)services in Sinatra or Rack using MySQL/Postgres, Redis, Unicorn/Puma,

Sidekiq/Shoryuken. At some point I got deeper into ops, got familiar with a wide range of AWS services from VPCs to CloudFormation and built our infrastructure around Ansible. Over the course of the last year, we shifted towards Kubernetes and Docker. I helped define new processes, handled technical interviews and performed product management tasks. I improved the overall performance of our systems and lived to see some beefy infrastructure

migration Sundays.

Feb. 2014 - Aug. 2014 Blacklane / Backend Developer (Ruby)

Nov. 2012 - Jan. 2014 Axonic / Full Stack Developer (Ruby on Rails)

A very enriching experience. I developed a fairly complex product (likomi.de) from scratch, while being the only developer on the project. Working closely with the CEO, I learned not just full stack development with Ruby on Rails but also what's important to customers, how to plan and how to build a product.

Dec. 2010 - Aug. 2012 Axonic / Full Stack Developer (PHP5, Symfony)

Apr. 2009 - Jul. 2010 Pi Technologies / Developer (PHP, CMS, Javascript)

Education

2010 - 2011 Karlsruhe Institute of Technology

M. Sc. Informatics (discontinued)

2006 - 2010 Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

B. Sc. Computer Science (240 ECTS Points) - 9.50/10